So today is Snickers ice cream. This
actually was requested when I did the
Almond Joy ice cream and my parents are
here visiting from the UK and they I
asked my mom anyway what ice cream she
wanted me to make and she also chose
Snickers.
So, if you have lived under a rock your
entire life and don't know what a
Snickers is, or maybe they're not
available in the country that you're
from, a Snickers is a nougat or nugar,
depending on where you're from. Um,
center with a layer of caramel with
peanuts on top, all encased in a milk
chocolate. They're one of my favorite
candy bars. We're going to deconstruct
this recipe. We're going to do a nougat
ice cream. Nugar ice cream with a
caramel peanut swirl with chocolate milk
chocolate stretchella.
So, it sounds delicious. I've never made
this, so this is the first time. What
are we going to need? So, for the base,
you're going to need 550 gram of 2%
milk. You can use whole milk. 550 grams
of cream, 33%. You can use 36%. If you
use double cream, so 50% cream, then
reduce that amount down to 450 grams.
You will need 66 g of skim milk powder,
110 g of the nouga nougar from within
the actual Snickers themselves, and 220
g of sugar. For the peanut caramel swell
element, you're going to need 150 g of
salted peanuts
and 200 g of caramel. That caramel will
consist of 250 g of sugar, 100 g of
water, 25 g of butter, 250 g of 33%
cream, and 50 g of invert sugar. So
that's glucose, corn syrup, golden
syrup, anything like that. And finally,
the milk chocolate stratella will
consist of 100 g of milk chocolate and 7
g of refined coconut oil. Refined
coconut oil important because we don't
want anything to taste coconut in this.
the refined element just means it's been
processed and impurities have been
removed and during that process the
taste of coconut actually comes out as
well. So if you want coconut oil to
taste of coconut use cold processed
coconut oil if you don't want the taste
then use refined. First thing we're
going to do is measure out our
ingredients and cut the core out of our
Snickers bars. Haven't got a hat on. But
let's start with our base. So, we're
going to start with 550 g of milk and
cream.
Into that, we're going to add our skim
milk powder, which is 66 g. 66 g. Then,
let's do our sugar. I'm going to use a
stabilizer. You don't have to if you
don't want to. There likely is enough
ingredients in the
nougat.
That means you don't need to, but
let's use some anyway. Into that, we are
going to add just
1 and 1/2 g of stabilizer. I'm using a
blend. Uh, if you want to know about
blending stabilizers, then there's a
video that I will link up here um that
will tell you or up here, wherever it
is, that will tell you all about
stabilizers. Tiny whisk.
And in that goes. So that's our base
apart from our nougat. I can't decide
how I want to say it. Nar. Nouga. In
England, most people I think or
generally most people my generation
would say nugar.
But with friends and Ross with his
nougat deficiency, I think the American
term has likely taken over. So So with
all those stirred, we're going to get
this on the hob and just get it warming
up. We've got stabilizer in this. hot
pressure stabilizer. It needs to go up
to 85 C 185F. So, let's get that going.
And whilst we do that, let's work on our
Snickers bars.
Knifey knifey. We're going to take off,
there's not a lot in there. Take off the
chocolate. And there is our nougat
layer. And we're going to take that off
specifically. That is what we want. We
don't want anything else in the base.
Right. What have we got? So, you're
going to need eight
Snickers bars or just get the big ones.
I'm going to make this in another video.
But for now, I'm going to get the rest
of these chopped up and then I'm going
to put them all that nougar nougat in
our base while it's heating up. So, I'll
come back once our ice cream base is
then up to 85C. So, while that is
heating up with our eight Snickers worth
of nugar in, we're going to get our
caramel prepared because this needs to
be made and cooled down as well. So, so
for our caramel, we are going to need
our scales. We're going to start with
our sugar, 250 g. And into that, we're
going to put 100 g of water. Swirl that
together. You can stir it at this stage.
It's absolutely fine.
And then finally, in goes our invert
sugar, which is 50 g. Now, we're going
to pop this on the hob and get this
turning into a nice golden brown color.
And whilst that is heating up, you're
going to deal with your peanuts. So,
we've got
150 g of peanuts. So, this is a
deconstructed Snickers bar
in ice cream form. Kind of like, you
know, Hon Bloom and Fowl style. So, in a
little food processor, pop your peanuts
in. And we're just going to pulse these.
We want them quite fine. We don't want
huge lumps of peanut in there. So, pulse
these. And let's see how long it takes.
Not long. That was, you know, 10 15
seconds worth of pulsing manually.
That's all it took. So, with the
pulsing, you've got a like a cornmeal
sized pieces of our peanut. Put that in
a container and we're going to wait for
our caramel to be done. There are a
couple of stages to the caramel. The
first is this light stage and then it
will start to thicken up and boil a bit
harder before it turns to that color.
That's where you want to be. So, with
the caramel off the heat, we have two
things to do and that is add our
butter. This is going to make it spit.
And
finally, our cream. Be careful doing
this. We're adding quite a bit of cream.
The the highfat caramels are what's
important for use in ice cream. That's
what really helps with the uh with the
invert sugar. That's what really helps
stopping it go going like solid as a
rock. Without that,
it goes really hard. Now, just keep
stirring this. If for some reason it
starts to cool down too much before all
your cream is incorporated, you can just
pop it back on heat just for a minute or
two. And that just warms that sugar back
up so that all that cream gets
incorporated. If you were to reduce the
amount of cream, so you know, cut it in
half, then it would all incorporate
really easily, but then it will also set
a little harder. So with our caramel
like that ready to go, we are going to
add in our
crushed peanuts.
Stir that together. Nice. And we are
simply going to pour that into a
container
like so. And rest that on there. Leave
this to cool down to room temperature.
And we are going to use that when we
dish up. So, so now that our base has
just cooled down a little bit, we can
get that into a container and we're
going to let this chill out overnight
cuz I want that flavor of that nouga
nougat to build as much as possible. I
will come back tomorrow when our base is
fully aged, our caramel is down to
temperature, and then we can get
churning. So, after it's completely
chilled down, we're going to stir it up
and pop it into our machine. I've
actually kind of overloaded the machine
a little bit here, but it's fine. Just
took a little bit longer. So, now we're
going to prepare our chocolate. Again,
we're using 100 g of milk chocolate. 5
to 7 g of coconut oil. And we're going
to melt that down in the microwave until
it's completely liquid and ready to use.
Out comes our peanut caramel. That's
ready to pour. At the end of our churn,
we're going to load in our stratella
chocolate and start dishing up whilst
layering in some of that glorious peanut
caramel. Finally, it's all going to go
in the freezer to harden off for a good
few hours because now's the time we're
going to dish it up. And it smells
incredible. It looks incredible. Let's
scoopy scoopy. As you can see, that
peanut caramel on top. Honestly, that is
just inspired. It's so so good. Doesn't
go hard in the freezer. It's ready to
eat straight off the spoon if you want
to cuz you know that's what I'm going to
do after this video is done. Nice
rolling ball into the bowl. Let's see
how this one looks.
[Music]
Deconstructed Snickers
ice cream. I God, I wish I'd call it
Marathon again. All those years ago, my
dad and I were talking about this, but
um Marathon was a much better name.
scooped perfectly.
Loads of kind of chocolate flex. This is
a stratutella
style chocolate addin. Uh stratutella is
originally a plain flavored gelato with
that chocolate fleck through it. But any
ice cream or gelato that you do that
same effect with you can call
stretchyella as well. this peanut
stuff. I'm going to put some on top
that caramel. Make it exactly as
instructed. It is perfect.
Doesn't go hard in the freezer and it's
purely because how it's made along with
that little bit of invert sugar to stop
it recrystallizing.
Man, that's tasty. Anyway, let's chat.
More eat.
It tastes just like it. The ice cream's
got a beautiful taste of
I'm still going to call it nugar because
I'm English, but I know that probably
80% of you watching this video will call
it nougat, but it's got that beautiful
flavor of the nougat. The milk chocolate
strautella mimics that milk chocolate
coating on the Snickers bar itself. That
peanut caramel.
Oh, it's far superior to the peanuts and
caramel in a Snickers bar. This is
delicious.
The peanut caramel recipe makes about
600 g worth. So, quite a bit. And as you
can see,
still lovely and fluid.
Truly a delicious ice cream. This is
just one take on a Snickers ice cream.
There's probably half a dozen different
ways you could go about this. You know,
a chocolate ice cream with peanut
brittle
caramel swirl. Still get that nougat
flavor in that ice cream as well. Loads
of different ways you could do this.
This is just one take.
This was a suggested flavor by a
actually quite a few people um channel
supporters as well as non- channel
supporters. So, if you want to see me
make a candy bar style ice cream, let me
know in the comments. Can you make this
in the Ninja Creamy? Yes, you absolutely
can make the base as normal and freeze
that in your Ninja Creamy containers.
Again, the icy treat ice cream maker as
well. Once you've got that, make your
caramel. You won't be able to do a
stratella in those spinning machines. It
it's it's impossible to do. But what you
can do is just take the chocolate,
finally chop it up, and then add that in
as a standard addin, and then when you
dish up, load your peanut caramel on
top, and you're right back here. So,
make sure you try this one. Delicious.
And I will see you next week. I have no
idea what I'm going to do next week. So,
[Music]
bye.